<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Melissa's blog</title>
    <link href="http://www.melissakaton.com/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://www.melissakaton.com" />
    <id>http://www.melissakaton.com/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Melissa Jade Katon</name>
        <email>hello@melissakaton.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>Why I chose to study at Open University</title>
    <link href="http://www.melissakaton.com/blog/open-university/why-open-university-student/index.html" />
    <id>http://www.melissakaton.com/blog/open-university/why-open-university-student/index.html</id>
    <published>2017-01-16T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was younger, a high school friend of mine said something to me with such determination that I wanted to defy it right away.</p>
<p>She said, “let’s face it, you’ll never leave Western Sydney. You’ll never afford to live anywhere else. Even if you become a lawyer, you’ll stay here and be a Western Sydney lawyer and never leave.”</p>
<div>

</div>
<!--more-->
<p>So naturally, within the first 2 years of graduating high school, I travelled to Fiji, Vietnam, Cambodia and Thailand, went to the London Olympics, visited Paris, Rome and London for the first time, and returned to my mum’s homeland, the Philippines, for the second time in my life (the first being when I was two years old).</p>
<p>I then moved out to an apartment at my university, UNSW, in Randwick, far out of Western Sydney. After that, I got it in my head that I would move to Europe and attend university in Belgium, since I was sick of law school and art school. Unlike in Sydney, you can enroll in any degree in Belgium without any prerequisites or certain marks (except for Medicine, for which you need to pass an exam). So, in 2013, I packed up my essentials and began my ‘language year’ in Leuven, Belgium to learn Dutch in order to attend university at the Katholieke Universiteit Leuven.</p>
<p>I managed to get a C1 in Dutch and did about a year and a half of Biology at the KUL. However, I wanted more freedom. I wanted to be able to travel whenever I want, wherever I want. During my time at the KUL, I couldn’t travel back to my home country, Australia, during the summer months, since we had exams during December and January. I lived centrally in Europe but felt pretty trapped and unable to travel as much as I wanted.</p>
<p>So, with my boyfriend’s encouragement, I enrolled in a BSc. Mathematics and Statistics at the Open University (in Great Britain), transferring all the science credits I’d accrued at the KUL.</p>
<p>So, what has this done for me?</p>
<p>For the first time in three years, I was able to travel home and spend Christmas with my family during the summer in 2016. I was able to bring my study books with me, and complete and submit assignments online. I still had great support from OU because my tutors are reachable by both email and telephone. I could study anywhere I wanted, and not feel tied to one place.</p>
<p>Since I’m already 24 years old, I was concerned that I wasn’t developing my career simply because I had changed degrees. Previously, I was bogged down with commuting, or going to classes at physical locations during the day, and managing a generally very all consuming student life. Since the Open University allows its students to continue working and study during their free time (you can pick and choose what sort of workload you want), I’m now able to start building a career and balace my day with work, study and play (play being, for example, swimming at Avoca Beach on boxing day back in NSW).</p>]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>5 reasons to be a digital nomad</title>
    <link href="http://www.melissakaton.com/blog/remote-work/5-reasons-to-be-a-digital-nomad/index.html" />
    <id>http://www.melissakaton.com/blog/remote-work/5-reasons-to-be-a-digital-nomad/index.html</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The constant, speedy development in STEM, particularly technology, has ensured that our working world has changed significantly. We no longer have to be tied to 9-5 jobs or to a small, dark cubicle in an office somewhere, counting down the days to your next holiday away to sunnier locations. It is now possible to be a ‘digital nomad,’ where you can develop a location-independent business and career pretty much <em>anywhere in the world</em> from your laptop!</p>
<p>Interested, but need a bit more convincing? Here are top 5 reasons why being a Digital Nomad blows having a 9-5 job out of the water.</p>
<div>

</div>
<!--more-->
<h3 id="you-can-work-in-any-location-in-the-world-as-long-as-you-have-internet-access.">1. You can work in any location in the world, as long as you have internet access.</h3>
<p>As a digital nomad, you develop a career that you can take along with you. If you have a laptop and access to the internet, you’re good to go!</p>
<p>A lot of digital nomad ‘hubs,’ like Chiang Mai in Thailand, are full of ‘coworking spaces,’ or spaces that you can rent on a monthy basis to use as an office. Such spaces are usually fitted out with computers and wifi, and can sometimes feature ammenities like a kitchen and shower.</p>
<p>For example, [Shambho Open Office] in Gent has a fancy rain shower, and many open offices on the Gent Coworking site have kitchens so you can fix yourself a snack when you need it. Pretty convenient!</p>
<h3 id="experience-the-world-and-have-a-fulfilling-life-without-waiting-for-time-off-or-retirement.">2. Experience the world and have a fulfilling life without waiting for time off or retirement.</h3>
<p>The beaten track usually involves graduating from university, applying and getting a graduate position, and working a 9-5 to climb up the career ladder. The entire time, you’re usually tied to one office in one place. Any exploration of the world is limited to the time off you get to go on vacation.</p>
<p>If you want to go on an even longer vacation, you often have to wait till retirement, but by then, you may no longer have the youthful energy you once had to hike to waterfalls in Laos or surf in Rio Di Janeiro.</p>
<p>Why wait till the end of your career to <em>fully enjoy the world around you?</em></p>
<p>As a digital nomad, you can explore the world while you’re still young <em>and</em> develop your career. Doesn’t that sound exciting?</p>
<h3 id="be-your-own-boss.">3. Be your own boss.</h3>
<p>Being a digital nomad requires a lot of self-discipline. It’s no secret that location independent work relies heavily on your time management abilities and motivation. However, if being able to decide when, where, and how you do your work, and you prefer to be a self-driven, independent worker, then being a digital nomad may be for you.</p>
<p>You can be your own boss, especially if you have your own business! Even as an employee of a company, you can still be your own boss by planning out how to achieve your goals and complete projects.</p>
<h3 id="you-can-tailor-your-career-and-working-hours-to-fit-your-lifestyle-and-needs.">4. You can tailor your career and working hours to fit your lifestyle and needs.</h3>
<p>This one is quite similar to no. 3, however it is appealing in its own right. Don’t mesh well with the typical 9-5 working hours? Have a family you would like to spend more time with at home, or have an illness that prevents you from working typical hours? What if you are a night owl, or prefer to use the daytime to go hiking and swimming and the nighttime to work?</p>
<p>Then being a digital nomad means that you can tailor your work to fit your lifestyle, instead of the other way round. Why not make your career work for you?</p>
<h3 id="being-a-digital-nomad-pushes-you-out-of-your-comfort-zone-making-you-develop-as-a-person.">5. Being a digital nomad pushes you out of your comfort zone, making you develop as a person.</h3>
<p>Finally, being your own boss and location-independent can definitely put you outside of your comfort zone. However, being outside of your comfort zone is exactly where you grow and develop as a person.</p>
<p>In fact, the skills that you gain from this lifestyle, like self-motivation, discipline, and independent thinking are all skills that are attractive to future employers. They are also skills that are vital for running your own business.</p>
<p>So why wait? If this lifestyle appeals to you, then start mapping out your dream job and make a plan to make it a reality!</p>]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
